Hi, and this lesson. I will show you how to use stop completions. I will go really in the tails about this feature and
We'll explain you all the options every thing you can do
And how you can use this feature
So normally top completion it means when you start typing something you'll get a suggestion and
Courseria, I will try to predict what code you want to write next depending on your file name
You'll code in your file like it's everything called context
Okay, what you can do with this feature you can
get some complete out of the completion you can
For example get some suggestions based on your recent changes
If you predict what new logic you want to add to your file or your project
You can modify a multiple line at once
I'll show you how it works and you can also jump within across the files and
Like for some coordinated edit, so you will see how it works. So let's start with a simple
top completion
Imagine I want to add a new currency right here, and when you click to the new line
Sorry, your automatic suggests to add a new currency. It's in the end review. Oh, let's accept it
Toss up the suggestion you need to click pop
and it's it again suggest us to
do some
That's some more currencies. There is also features you can partially accept the suggestion
For example, if you want to accept only I know a few of them or for example, you will need to add the actual you will need to edit
show rates and
But to enable this feature we need to go to the settings because it's disabled by the default
you will click on top section and you see partial accept and
What it will does is that I have the next word of suggestions we are command plus right arrow key
If you swim those instead of command, you can use control and you enable this feature
Okay, let's see how it works
Okay, it
The suggestion only one currency right now, but not the problem. I click just comment right and you see I
Accepted only the currency name
And then a for example can provide a different rate for example one dot so to six
and it can
Use the next suggestion for example word by word. Yeah
And imagine it's enough for us and we want to decline the suggestion. We can use escape
key just decline it
for example to
Start type in something different
video just
Ignore the suggestion
Now, I just type start type something and just ignore the suggestion
Okay, let's save it
Now I want to show you how we can do the code changes across the file for example when you view
Change some existing code
in multiple places
Or imagine you want to rename our variables make it more short and just want to rename it to
From
Yep
And you see after your name the transferable cursor scene. Okay, you also have two currency variable
You might want to rename it as well
And you use it below
In the check so you might also want it to rename I will click top to accept all these renameans
And when I click top one more time you will see also it's a just a change it in the
Rest of the file
Oh, and in the right side you see the pop pop pop up which highlights in the difference. Yeah, it's a light
It's very both how it how it's now and how it will be you can click top also accept it
Okay
And as you see we were jumping
Across the file
Yeah
Predict the next editing location in the files and when you click top you just jump to the next location
For example, it can if you have a few files it
Can suggest you also jump to the another files which are related and
You don't need to make it open it. I just can show you
Maybe
I'll show you a bit later it
But you know this feature is exist
For example also you have
You can use auto import feature
Oh, when you start the for example when you have a few files and you will need to
Use a method from another file. Oh, let's create
Some utils like
RNC
Utils dot jazz
Oh, let's write some function example doesn't matter. I want to use some
Oh
Might be let's write
format
A currency
For example, and let's express it
So it's a format currency utl which we can use right here and for example if
I will use the format currency for example. I want to format this currency right here in a console log
I also type in the method name
format currency you see it suggests to use format currency
utl
and apply it to the rest places
And now if we scroll down
top to jump here on so I just click top
But it doesn't import it
Uh-huh, okay
Yeah, when we just click it so you see it added an import
And it's I'm not always do it from the first attempt. Oh, I did it only but
As you see when I just removed one symbol and type it in one more time
It suggests us to import it from
From the file so it can also add some automatic imports
Uh, okay, but it works much better for the TypeScript files and for the Python
So okay, what else you can use
For example, if you use some TypeScript files
You can go to some
definitions
for example
Like when you highlight the function you will see the type definition and you can go to the directly to this file
For example
But when it using TypeScript files, so I can show it how it works
So you can just believe me
Okay, let's now open settings and I will show you what other features you can use. The password type you can
Enable or disable type completions or if you just don't like it the suggestions you can disable it
As the partial acceptance we have already covered it
Suggestions file commenting for example when you write in a comment you can also get some suggestions
It might correct your mistakes for example. I'm spreading
If you don't like you can also turn it off
Okay
For example our imports automatically import necessary models for TypeScript
You can also it's enabled by default and if you don't if you'd like to use it for Python
You can also turn it on but it's in better still
Uh, okay
And for example
I think this is everything I want to show you
Let me check
Okay, I hope this lesson was useful for you and now you know how to use type completions what options you can use
How to partial accept it decline it or accept I will do edits across
Across the multiple places in one file
So and see you in the next lesson